Today we're talking about hooks. If you
want your videos to perform better, the
most valuable thing you could do is
build a hook writing system. This is a
framework and process for writing killer
hooks every single time. Now, look, I've
created some of the most popular hook
trainings on the internet. I've
literally studied thousands of the top
performing videos. And I've personally
done billions of views and racked up
over a million followers just because my
hookw writing was so dialed. But the
problem is getting all that hook
knowledge into one AI workflow that
actually works for everyone has been
pretty tough. The good news is I think I
finally figured it out and I'm going to
give it away for free in this video. I
call it the hook machine. It's an AI
workflow that combines data and advanced
storytelling principles to help you
write winning hooks every single time.
So in this video, I'm going to walk
through how the hook machine works, why
it works so well, and the exact
step-by-step workflow that you can use
to implement it today. All right, let's
dive in. Now, before I do anything, let
me just explain why AI hookw writing
doesn't usually work. It's actually very
simple. When you write hooks with AI,
the LLMs just aren't optimized for short
form social data. Unless you train them
extensively, they just don't understand
how to write persuasively for social
media. This is why when you dump in your
topic into a cold AI chat and say,
"Write me hooks," it ends up horrible.
They always just end up sounding super
generic and never compelling. Now, most
people have accepted that, but instead
they try the copypaste method where they
take a super viral hook from a creator
all the way in this niche and they try
to copy paste it and apply it to their
niche. But here's the funny thing. When
you do these crazy copypaste from one
niche all the way over to the other,
they usually don't work either because
the psychology doesn't translate. The
format crossover doesn't work well. I
mean, even the grammar usually isn't
working when you copy paste it. And yet
all these people try these straight
copypaste hook clones because all the
fake gurus told them to. So what is the
real way to use AI but actually solve
the hook problem? The solve in my
opinion is the hook machine. The hook
machine is my four-step process that
combines data with storytelling
principles to give you the best chance
at writing an original hook that
actually works every time. By the way,
I'm also just giving you the prompt and
the skill file linked below. It's free
so you can have that. you can grab that
ripet and claw and you'll be good to go.
Now, I want to go through a live example
and show you exactly how I use this and
it coming to life. So, the very first
step before you can make this work, you
need to have a Sandcastle's account.
Without the MCP, you can't pipe the
social data in. We can't deep analyze
the videos. We can't run the data loop.
Everything kind of breaks. So, step
number one, you have to have a
Sandcastle's account. There's a link
below if you want to join. I'm going to
assume moving forward that you do have
at least a Sand Castle's Pro account.
All right. The next step is that we need
to set up the Sand Castle's MCP. You
have the Sand Castle's account and you
have Claude, but we have to build a pipe
connecting them so that we can
automatically tell Sand Castles to do
stuff from Claude. Now, if you've
already set up the Sandcastle MCP cuz
you only have to do it once, go ahead
and skip to the next section. If you
haven't set it up, I put together a
video that I've linked in the
description, help.sandcastle.ai/MCP.
It takes 2 minutes to set it up. Very
easy to follow the instructions, but you
need to make sure you follow that and
set this up before you move forward. Go
ahead and pause this video and get the
MCP set up and then come back and keep
watching. All right, so at this point in
the video, I'm going to assume everybody
has a Sandcastle's at least pro
subscription and has the MCP set up. Now
we're good to go. This is going to be
sick. All right, so now we're in Claude
and we're going to go through a live
demo of the hook machine. This is like
my favorite workflow I've ever built. So
we're going to do is you're going to
copy paste in the prompt that I have
linked below in the description. I'm
going to copy paste that in as well. I'm
going to use co-work. What you see is
the desktop app for Claude. If you're
not on the desktop app, go to
claude.com/d download. Download the
desktop app. You need to be on the
desktop app in order to run co-work or
code. So, here we go. We've got this
prompt. We're going to paste it in and
let it rip. Okay. So, what you're going
to see if you if you're not really
familiar with Claude, it's going to
build in the progress tab up in the
upper right. It's going to build the
flow in a minute, but first it's going
to tee this up. So, it says, "I'm the
hook machine by Callaway. Here's what
I'm going to do. You're going to give me
social channels, and I'm going to do
three things for you. I'm going to build
a hook format library." This is a bonus.
This is like it's just going to list all
the top performing hooks with the Mad
Lib for you. You can export and save
that out just as a bonus. It's going to
create that personalized grading rubric,
which is how it evaluates good versus
bad hooks. Then it's going to build a
hook generation engine where you can
drop in any topic and it will write new
hooks for you. So, what we're going to
do is just to keep it quick, we're going
to do the top 10 videos from me as well
as three other competitors. So, we're
going to do grab the top 10 videos
from these channels. And I'm going to
say ignore any videos about personal
life that are not related to the topic.
And I'm just doing this cuz I don't want
to waste any credits or grab any hooks
that are like about a a personal vlog
that's like not on topic for me. Okay.
So, first I'm going to grab my own
channel. So, we've got that here. And
I'm just going to paste it in right
here.
Then I'm going to grab three
competitors. I'm going to do Peter
Visuals. This guy's faceless. I don't
know who this is, but pretty impressive.
I know he watches my stuff, so he's
probably going to see this bonus
footage. New guy, growing fast. I like
this guy's vibe. And then we're going to
do Brier, the homie. Now, all these are
different styles, right? So, when you do
hook analysis, you may want to run this
flow just on you alone because that's
really the way to get the best data is
like just you. But you can also run it
with other people as well. And that's
why we segment the analysis out across
the different people because Brier style
is a little bit different. The bonus
footage a little bit different than me.
So it's like the hooks rhythm may not be
what I want. But we'll see. So here we
go. This is going to analyze 40 videos
in total. 10 per channel times four
channels, which is what I said. That's
40 credits roughly 10 minutes of
processing time. Now, if you already
have some of these processed on the back
end, which I do, it'll tell you on the
next step, oh, we didn't actually have
to run 40 credits. It was all good cuz
you already spent the credits before. So
it's not going to double charge you. One
last thing, and this is really
important. Do you want me to include all
the videos or screen out any brand
deals? Typically, any video with below a
2% engagement rate, that's a high
performer, has paid spend behind it,
that will artificially inflate the video
and give you a false sense of what will
work. We like to screen these out by
default. Are you okay with that? Of
course I am. I wrote the rules. Yes.
Screen out brand deals. And then, just
to confirm, you said ignore any videos
about personal life. The topic here, da
da da. Is that right? And we'll say yes.
Let's let it rip. So now what it's going
to do is it's going to go and it's going
to find do you have those channels in
your watch list in Sandcastles? If you
don't, it's going to go find the
channels in the Sand Castle's database,
add them to your watch list so we can
run this. Any channel you give, we can
do this for. There's going to be no lag.
It may give you a notice that we don't
have them in the database. So we need to
live add them, scrape their whole
backlog, import them, and then run this
process for you. It will let you know
that if it needs to. I know that all
four of these people are in there. And
so you can see what it's doing is it's
looking, do I need to add any of these
people to the watch list? It likely
won't. All four channels are already in
your watch list. Now pulling top videos
from each. So this Sandcastle MCP is
magic. I've mentioned this before
already. If you've used Appify to try to
like lightweight connect your social
media, you see all those people on
TikTok that are like, I built a social
media marketing engine using Cloud. Like
what they really said is they connected
via Apify and they were able to scrape
the metrics and like the captions and
it's actually very surface level. It's
good for like ranking the videos that
are doing the best, which we can
obviously do for free, but you're not
getting any deep analysis. So, what this
does is all that stuff that you're
paying Apify for, we give it to you for
free. Unlimited for free. The scraping,
the metrics, the captions, all for free.
What we charge credits for is the deep
analysis. We're doing advanced
processing with the transcript, the
idea, the topic, the hook format, the
storytelling format, the visual layout,
all the metrics, everything we're doing
advanced, as much as you could do.
That's a credit per video. And so, if
you've set up Ampify, this will blow
your mind what this can do. So, as I
mentioned in the upper right, the
progress, the way Claude works is it
starts to build this kind of like
project plan for you. So, you can see
it's already added the four channels to
the watch list. Now, it's pulling the
top 10 videos per channel. It's going to
make sure all the videos are qualifiers,
right? So, if any are about personal
background or any of them are off topic,
it's going to screen those out. If any
are paid brand deals, it'll screen those
out. Then, it's going to go and sort the
top 10 by person. So, it's not going to
mash all 40 together. It's going to go
list of 10. We want to keep them
segmented. As I mentioned, the hook
styles are kind of different per person.
So, we're going to keep them segmented.
And then it will delineate a line. The
ones above that line are winners. The
one below those lines are losers. And
so, it's going to try to figure out like
where are the winning hooks within the
top 10 videos. Is there a break point
that we find like super winners? And
it's going to go through that process
and then the rest. Now, the cool thing
about the Sandcastle's MCP is that it
has access to all these different tools.
So, I believe there's 24 different tools
that are baked into the MCP. So right
here you can see it's hitting the
channel recap. We also have the analyze
tool which it'll be using. That's the
tool that we actually run the analysis
via Sand Castles to Claude. We also have
the credit tool. We have the hooks tool.
We have a format tool. There's there's
so many tools, right? So it's giving us
an update now that says the Callaway
Marketing 10, the Peter visuals and
Brier 10 have been analyzed. The bonus
footage is the only one with gaps. So
it's completing those now. So you can
see it's firing the analysis tool right
here. It's concurrently analyzing all
six of the remaining bonus footage
videos. So, it's already has 34 done. If
you already have the videos analyzed on
the Sand Castle's web side, this will be
extremely quickly. Any ones it has to
fill the gap for, it'll take about 1 to
2 minutes per video and it's running
those concurrently. So, this should take
about another minute. One other tip for
anyone doing this, if the analyze
process takes a long time because you're
pulling a bunch of videos that have not
been analyzed, you can always go into
the Sand Castle's web app and you can
manually analyze or bulk analyze the
videos you want. it's faster in the web
app and then you can export that data
into a CSV and drop that in here which
will actually save you some time on this
first analysis piece. So you kind of
have two ways of doing it. The analysis
is just faster in the web app than it
would be through the data pipe cuz I has
to keep going back and forth. So now
we're moving to the next step which is
sorting the winners and losers. You can
see in the upper right we've got three
done. We're now sorting. So if we go
down here's the top 10 that it took from
me and it's identified some as winners
and some as losers. And the reason or
the way it did that was it noted a
natural break point in the views between
video four and five. And so what it's
saying is number 1 2 3 4 those are big
bangers that we should analyze the hook
for. The rest were not breakouts
relative to the others. So it did that
for my videos. And then for every other
channel it does it for break it out as
well. So for Peter Visuals there are
five with a clear break point. For bonus
footage there are four. Although he's a
bit smaller. So you can see like four or
five. These are these are kind of
similar. So you can change the
delineation point in a second, but for
what it did, it did the top four. And
then for Brier, it also pulled four.
There's a clear break point. So content
is just like anything else. It's 8020,
right? So typically there's going to be
a few videos that are huge bangers that
drive a majority of the growth. Those
are the ones that we want to study and
extract the principles out of. So if we
scroll down now, it's asking us, okay,
it did the summary. It screened out paid
videos, which like Peter visuals, gamma
post, 0% engagement, clear clear paid
videos. So, it's screened that out
because we don't want to evaluate that
hook or value it too highly if it's
actually a mid-performer that was just
boosted. So, now it's saying, do you
want to adjust the win or loser line?
I'm going to keep what it did because
all of them except for maybe bonus
footage look good. So, we'll say keep
the line. We'll move to the next piece.
So, now that it's keeping the line, what
it's going to do is it's going to
analyze all the ones above the line and
it's going to try to find the core
principles for why those hooks did well.
It's going to first do them separately.
one for me, one for Brier, one for bonus
footage, one for Peter visuals. And then
it's going to see, are there any core
principles or pillars that are the same
across all of us? Those are a great sign
to combine with kind of the universal
principles. So that's what it's doing
now is it's trying to evaluate all of
these. Now, it already has the
transcript, the hook, it already did all
the analysis. So now it's just running
the meta analysis on top of the data
that we have in here. All right, so here
we go. Now it's starting to run through
the analysis for each person. So, what
it's doing is it's looking for a couple
different buckets. It's looking for
psychology takeaways, trigger words and
framing takeaways, grammatical
takeaways, and then non-obvious
takeaways. It's going to do that for
each person, and then it's going to
combine comprehensive insights across.
So, for me, for example, these were the
four it looked at. It said these were
the six kind of losers. For on the
psychology front, it says winners attach
a concrete outcome to a constrained
input. For example, 30 days of content
in 30 minutes. Losers lean on series
branding without a standalone value
promise inside the first sentence. So
it's like okay on the psychology front,
winners versus losers. Trigger words
versus framing. Winners use actually
everyday crushing right now easiest.
Losers are using vague superlatives. On
the grammatical structure, winners are
declarative and frontload the payoff.
That's actually a really interesting
insight. Here's how to here's how to do
X and Y versus the losers which are kind
of delaying the takeaway and they have
no identity. So here's a pattern. When
Callaway names a specific outcome, the
video wins. When he leans on episode
branding alone, it syncs 50%. Like,
that's a very insightful takeaway just
on mine alone. And this only analyzed
four videos. Imagine if you just did
your own and you ripped 50 videos and
you had it run all 50. The amount of
rigor in the analysis would be pretty
insane. Now, let's look at Peter
visuals. Took these five. The
psychology. Peter's entire framework is
case study as content. The hook is the
stat, but not all stats win equally.
Winners pair the stat with a second
sentence amplifier, like a comparison or
contrarian reframe. The losers state the
stat and stop. So like right away I'm
like, "Okay, that's pretty clear." Every
single one of his videos is this case
study format, but it's working super
well when he adds this kind of amplifier
on the top or on the second sentence.
Trigger words and framing. He uses
magnitude language and like the like
counts as additional proof points. The
exact numbers that he use matter. 90 to
120 million outperforms 19 to 40. So
bigger evidence is better. That's pretty
intuitive, but like clear that it
confirmed it. Then it goes through the
grammatical structure. Here's an anti
pattern. Audio clip openers where the
video opens with reference videos clip
instead of his framing. These
underperform by roughly 60%. Again, very
insightful, not obvious. And this is not
the type of thing you would get from
scraping off the top. You need the
actual transcript and the the visual
analysis to be able to get this deep.
So, it does that for him. I'm not going
to go through all these just to save you
guys time, but bonus footage. It's going
to do the same thing here. Briar, it's
going to do the same thing here for him.
You could do this for every single
competitor that you have. Now, it's
going to move to the cross channel
synthesis. We didn't read all these, but
I bet if you read every single one of
these, you'd be like, "Oh, okay. It's
kind of common that across these three
people, they seem to do the same thing
psychologically." Right? So, now what
it's doing is it's going to look for any
common attributes across all four. And
what it's assuming is all of these
people are close competitors. And so,
you actually want some similarity, like
you want to find if there is a a similar
attribute that you can use. So, here we
go. So it says after running the
channels independently here are the
patterns that show up in two or more of
the channels. First is specificity beats
abstraction. All four channels show when
spec when you're specific it works
better. Good insight. Number two the two
sentence amplifier structure appears
both in Peter visuals and me and
somewhat brier. So it's like you state
something and then you give an amplifier
in the second sentence. I tend to do
that a lot. Peter does that a lot. It's
noticing that commonality. Number three,
avoid throat clearing openers. Brier
plus bonus footage plus Callaway all
show this. You're not like wasting time
or delaying the value. Pretty
interesting. And then here's a few
others. Confident declaratives beat
hedged questions. Brier, Callaway, Peter
all confirm. Winners say things are
losers ask questions. So again, these
are all like really compelling and
interesting insights that I would not
have known right off the rip. I can kind
of gauge my own stuff, but comparing it
to others, this is what an LLM is really
designed for. So there's a couple
others. Here's some divergences where we
do different things. Okay, cool. So now
what we did is we're taking the
universal principles. These are the
eight principles that I believe to be
true when it comes to hook storytelling
that just crush every time. If you've
watched a lot of my videos, you'll
recognize most of these. These are
common attributes that tend to be true.
Then we're adding on the custom
principles that we've extracted from
this data. Now, if we would have pulled
50 videos from each of these channels,
all four of these channels, maybe this
would have slightly changed. If we would
have pulled other channels, this would
have definitely changed. If we would
have pulled just my channels, this would
have changed. So, you can run this a
bunch of times to get different
variations of your hook rubric, the
greater. And you're going to use that to
write different hooks. So, this can be a
oneandone if you analyze a bunch of
videos, but it doesn't have to be a
oneanddone is my point. And so, look at
how many kind of universal principles
we're adding just from this. Okay, cool.
So, that's the rubric. Eight principles,
11 custom principles with sources
tagged. If anything looks off, we say
so. If not, we say let's continue. So,
I'm going to say continue.
All right. So, now we're continuing from
here. And so, first, what it's going to
do is it's going to build a library of
all the winning hooks. This is just like
a bonus takeaway. Like, you don't even
need this for the hook machine, but I
just included it because if you want to
summarize all the ones you just analyzed
via the credits, it has that here,
right? So, for me, it's like here's one
video, the original hook, the format,
second video, original hook, format, and
you could just copy this. You could drop
this into a different chat, save this as
a skill. You could export this, upload
this somewhere else. Right? So, you've
got all of the hooks that you just
analyzed right here. Mine, Peter,
visuals, bonus footage, Brier, they're
all here. That's just a bonus, like I
said. Now, where we're at here is it's
time to write a topic. And so, the whole
point of this is that you want to build
a hook machine that you can just write
any topic and it will give you winning
hooks. And it will use some of the data,
some of these proven formats, and it
will write its own using those
principles. So, let's just do a hook
example. So, I'm going to say I want to
make a video about this concept,
dopamine ladders.
This explains the six levels of dopamine
that get released when someone watches a
video. This is how you make people
addicted to content. Let's just say like
this is a topic that I want to make a
video about. This is a unique topic I
validated. I'm like, I want to make a
video about this. Boom. So, I add that
topic in there. Now, you can add a lot
more research if you wanted just for the
brevity of this and like to show the
simplistic workflow. I'm like, okay, I'm
just going to drop like a couple
thoughts, couple sentences. So, now it's
going to write me hooks about this idea
of dopamine ladders. What it's going to
do is it's going to give me up to five
hooks per person. So, five for me, five
for Brier, five for bonus footage, and
five from Peter Visuals based on the
winning hook formats. Now, it's not
going to do five if there's only two
that won, right? Right? So, it's only
it's going to go up to five based on the
ones that actually analyzed. That's why
more videos is better. It's going to
give me all of those. Now, it's not just
going to copy paste the format. It's
going to take the format and reskin it
using our principles to write it close
but not exactly. It's also going to only
pick the winning formats that match this
type of topic. So, it's intuitive enough
to know, well, this is kind of like a
theoretical psychology concept. So, if
there's a random hook format that's
about stats or a case study, it's not
going to be a match. So, we shouldn't
even use it. So, it's going to rule out
some of those as well. So, it's going to
give you a list based on each of the
channels, and then it's going to write
its own list of five that I find are
typically the best. So, usually it's
like your own channel. It's going to
give good ones. The originals are going
to be good ones. And then it's hit or
miss depending on the channels that you
actually pull because like I said,
Brier, bonus footage, these guys yap and
so they're more long-winded and I tend
to be a little bit tighter and I don't
want to have these like rambly hooks.
Not in like a bad way. They just talk
with more words per sentence. So, those
might not be a fit for me. So, let's
just see what it comes up with. So, here
we go. Right away it's saying heads up.
Peter Visuals library is mostly case
study stat. Dopamine ladders is a
conceptual framework with no external
stat. So four of his five formats fail
at the compatibility screening. So it's
not going to give me examples. And I
actually like that because forcing a
case study hook template into a
psychology breakdown is actually exactly
what I was saying in the beginning of
this video. You want to avoid this
crossover format crosspollination just
does not work. So it's intuitive enough
to know that which I think is pretty
powerful. So, first it says, okay, for
my own videos, only two of the four fit.
So, here are the example hooks it wrote.
Here's how to release six levels of
dopamine in 60 seconds of video. Or,
dopamine driven content is outperforming
everything else. So, here's the easiest
framework for triggering six layers of
it. I kind of like the second one. I
don't really love the first one. So,
let's keep going. This is the one Peter
Visuals format that actually worked. One
level of dopamine is bad for attention.
Three levels is good, and six levels is
what makes people addicted. That that
might actually work. Bonus footage. I
studied 200 of the most addicting videos
on the internet, but a comment said,
"You're overthinking it." And the truth
is, they all hit the same six dopamine
triggers I now use in every script. I
think there could be something here.
It's a bit long-winded. If you force me
to make your next video addictive in six
steps is exactly what I would do. This
is this is decent. That's actually
decent. How to turn any boring topic
into an addictive video because dopamine
driven hooks are on fire right now. Eh,
I'd probably skip this. Now, one thing I
didn't mention is this is grading these
hooks based on the criteria in the
rubric, right? So, it's rating these
A's. It's not going to pull ones that
are bad fits. I've coded it. So, it's
like, yo, if it's a C or below, don't
even give it to me. And so, that's why
you're seeing these grades. This one
from Brier, if you held a gun to my head
and said you had to make a video
addictive in the next 24 hours, I'd
basically give you my six level dopamine
ladder. This could work for a yapper.
It's a little long for me. For dopamine
hooks, single trigger is Dtier. Nobody
actually stays for one trigger anymore.
I don't love that. I have bad news for
all of you who copy hook templates.
Single trigger hooks are dead in 2026
because dopamine has gone multi-layered.
And I don't really love that either. So,
there's only a couple in this list that
I really like. Let's see the originals.
There are six levels of dopamine your
brain hits while watching a video, and
most creators only trigger one of them.
That's pretty good. Most creators
trigger one type of dopamine in a video.
The viral ones trigger six. That's
pretty good. Some videos release six
types of dopamine in under a minute.
That's why they feel impossible to stop
watching. There's something good there
as well. Addictive videos don't have one
good hook. They have a dopamine ladder
and there are exactly six rungs. Eh, I
don't love exactly six rungs. Six levels
of dopamine separate the videos, but
separate the videos people watch from
the videos people can't stop watching.
That's like a good tweet. I don't know
if that's good for a hook. So, the point
is what we have here now is based on
what I put in the topic, we generated
hook options for each of these people
plus originals. Now, as you can see, the
more videos that you analyze, the deeper
this goes. And so, you actually want to
have a lot more videos in the hopper,
right? So, here we only are getting two,
three, three, we're only getting like
seven. Well, there's one more, nine or
so that fit because of the given topic
that we have. If you analyze your whole
backlog and then you've got a ton to
pull from, you'll have so many more
options. So, this is kind of like the
initial list of hooks. Now, as a backup,
where I think this closes the loop for
sure is around this original rewrite.
So, what I can now do is I can say, you
know what, I don't really like any of
these, but this this one gave me an
interesting idea. I'm going to go play
around on my side and like write
something that's a derivative of this.
I'm going to paste it in and then I want
this to grade my hook against the
criteria and also rewrite it for me. So
I'm going to paste in let's just let's
just come up with one now. So I'll say
this is how you get people actually
addicted to your content. It's called
dopamine ladders.
And once you learn it, you'll never look
at content
the same way again. Let's just say this
is something I came up with. So, I'm
going to say go. Now, what it's going to
do is it's going to grade this. And I
bet this is going to give it like a B
minus or a C++. It's a little
long-winded. It's not specific enough,
but let's see. It's going to grade it,
and it's going to explain why it gave me
the grade that it gave me. Here we go.
It gave me a B. So, it said line by line
breakdown. This is how you get people
actually addicted to your content. It
covered this. The distillation was weak.
This is how you is soft. No specificity.
Like I was saying, credibility anchored
none. So, it was pretty weak on the
first line. It's called dopamine
ladders. And once you learn it, you
never look at content the same way
again. Good. But it's vague and it's
missing a concrete asset. Why not
higher? Here it is. Then it's like,
okay, here's three versions of a rewrite
that could improve it. Number one, this
is how you get people actually addict to
your content. It's called dopamine
ladders, and there exactly six rungs.
Why it's stronger? Because this is
specific. Number two, most creators
trigger one type of dopamine in their
videos. The addictive ones use a sixle
ladder. Ooh, that's pretty good. That's
my favorite so far right there. I study
200 of the most addictive videos online,
and they all do the same thing. climb
six rungs of a dopamine ladder. There's
something interesting there. But uh this
is the best right here for sure. I would
use that one in my video. So the point
is like if you run this workflow and you
just use your own videos, right? That's
that's the real like if I'm if I'm being
honest, the real way to do this is I
make a 100 videos on my own. I analyze
all 100. I pipe all 100 into this. And
you could just if you want to avoid the
Sand Castle's credits, you still want to
use the MCP, but you could just drop in
the transcripts of the 100. That could
also kind of work. Although we do a lot
of processing visually, so you kind of
want the sand castles analysis. You
analyze your hundred, then it runs the
top 20. It grabs the there's going to be
a breakpoint probably for 10 or 12 or
15. You're going to give it a topic and
you're likely going to have a lot of
other versions, other videos that map to
that topic. It's going to write you
hooks inspired by that remixed here and
originals, but the originals are only
going to be based on my storytelling
principles and your account, not the
competitors. Interestingly, the more
competitors you add in one analysis, the
muddier it gets. So, you might want to
run this four times with separate single
competitor each time and have like the
Brier hook writer, the bonus footage
hookwriter, the Callaway hook writer,
and you go to them separately because I
have a feeling that when you combine all
the insights, it does dilute to the
average. But when you do it one at a
time, it makes it super clear. What I
love though is this. I can put in my own
hook and it will grade it against the
criteria that we built from the data and
then rewrite it to tweak. The rewrites
are like my favorite part of this. So
once you have this done, you don't have
to keep running the entire flow again.
Like I could just drop in another topic
here, right? So it's like throw me a
different topic. So once you have this
in here, what you can do is you can
actually set up a project in co-work
with this and then just hit that project
over and over or you could just do this
in the same thread. This will burn a
bunch of tokens though if you like have
to keep running the whole thing. So,
multiple ways to do it, but like this
this is the best way I found to use
data, but also originality and writing
to get the AI machine anchored to make
hooks that actually win. Hopefully, you
guys got a lot out of that. I'm going to
do a bunch more workflows like this
where it's in-depth and I'm kind of like
more more like raw, like I'm on a
podcast kind of riffing, less like
performative. So, if you guys liked me
on this and you liked seeing this
walkthrough, please like let me know in
the comments. Leave the give me the give
me the mustache chef in there and that
you know we're cooking. So, that's
that's what I want to see. All right,
guys. That's all I've got for this
video. I tried a little something new
here where I went more in depth with the
workflow. Really shared my screen, like
showed literally everything I'm doing.
If you like that and you want me to make
more of these content meets AI
workflows, drop a little chef emoji. I'm
happy to do more of these less theory,
more tactics. Just let me know if you
like this or not. As always, I'm trying
my absolute best to push the envelope
and give you guys stuff that you don't
typically see. My goal is to give you
the stuff that most people put behind a
payw wall that I'll just give you for
free. If you've been around here for a
while, you know my goal is to help a
million people generate over a million
dollars with content. That's a trillion
dollars in market impact. That's kind of
what I'm going for. In order to do that,
I got to give these in-depth things for
free. So, please drop in the comments
what else I can cover that would help
you unblock or move forward with
content. If you're a business owner or
creator and you're trying to grow with
content, you can probably tell this is
going to be one of the best channels for
you. Please make sure to subscribe and
I've got a ton of free stuff in the
description. Make sure to check that
out. For this video in particular, I've
got the free Claude prompt for the hook
machine, the Claude skill for the hook
machine, as well as a bunch of other
resources. So, make sure to grab that,
make sure to use it, and we'll do
everything we can to get you guys
growing faster. All right, that's all
I've got for this video. We will see you
guys on the next one. Peace.